notoriously: adv. （尤指因坏事）众所周知地
Lesson 51, predicting the future, predicting the future is notoriously difficult.
第51课，预测未来，预测未来是困难的。
Who could have imagined in the mid-1970s? For example, that by the end of the 20th century,
谁能想象在1970年代中期？例如，到20世纪末
computers would be as common in people's homes as TV sets.
电脑在人们的家中与电视机一样普遍。
In the 1970s, computers were common enough, but only in big business, government departments,
在1970年代，计算机很普遍，但仅在大型企业，政府部门，
mainframe: n.   主机，中央处理机
and large organizations. These were the so-called mainframe machines.
和大型组织。这些是所谓的大型机机。
Mainframe computers were very large indeed, often occupying whole air-conditioned rooms,
大型计算机确实很大，经常占用整个空调房间，
full-time: adj. 专职的, technician: n.   技师, software: n.   软件
employing full-time technicians and run on specially-written software. Though these large
雇用全职技术人员并运行专门编写的软件。尽管这些很大
machines still exist, many of their functions have been taken over by small, powerful personal computers.
机器仍然存在，许多功能已被小型，强大的个人计算机接管。
Commonly known as PCs, in 1975, a primitive machine called the Altair was launched in the USA.
通常被称为PC，1975年，一台名为The Altair的原始机器在美国推出。
It can properly be described as the first home computer, and it pointed the way to the future.
它可以正确地描述为第一台家用计算机，并指出了通往未来的道路。
This was followed at the end of the 1970s by a machine called an Apple. In the early 1980s,
在1970年代末，这是一台名为Apple的机器。在1980年代初期，
the computer giant IBM produced the world's first personal computer. This ran on an
计算机巨头IBM生产了世界第一台个人计算机。这是在
Microsoft: n.   （美国）微软公司
operating system called DOS. Produced by a then small company named Microsoft,
操作系统称为DOS。由当时名为Microsoft的小型公司生产
the IBM personal computer was widely copied. From those humble beginnings,
IBM个人计算机被广泛复制。从那些谦虚的开始，
user-friendly: adj. 容易操作的，好用的, multimedia: adj. 多媒体的
we have seen the development of the user-friendly home computers and multimedia machines which are.
我们已经看到了用户友好的家用计算机和多媒体机器的开发。
In common use today, considering how recent these developments are, it is even more remarkable
如今，考虑到这些发展的最新情况，这是更引人注目的
that as long ago as the 1960s. An Englishman, Leon Bagrid, was able to predict some of the uses of
早在1960年代之前。英国人莱昂·巴格里德（Leon Bagrid）能够预测
computers which we know today. Bagrid dismissed the idea that computers would learn to think for
我们今天知道的计算机。巴格里德驳斥了计算机会学会思考的想法
themselves and would rule the world, which people like to believe in those days. Bagrid for saw
他们本身并将统治世界，人们喜欢在那些日子里相信的世界。巴格里德锯
time when computers would be small enough to hold in the hand. When they would be capable of
计算机将足够小的时间握在手中。当他们有能力
alternative: adj. 选择的
providing information about traffic jams and suggesting alternative. Roots, when they would be
提供有关交通拥堵的信息并提出替代方案。根，什么时候
diagnose: v.   诊断, relieve: v.   减轻
used in hospitals to help doctors to diagnose illnesses. When they would relieve office workers and
在医院中用于帮助医生诊断疾病。当他们解雇办公室工作人员和
accountant: n.   会计, repetitive: adj. 重复的, clerical: adj. 办公室工作的
accountants of dull, repetitive clerical work, all these computer uses have become commonplace.
沉闷，重复的文书工作的会计师，所有这些计算机使用都变得很普遍。
Of course, Leon Bagrid could not possibly have forcing the development of the internet.
当然，莱昂·巴格里德（Leon Bagrid）不可能迫使互联网的发展。
The worldwide system that enables us to communicate instantly with anyone in any part of the world.
世界范围内的系统，使我们能够立即与世界上任何地方的任何人进行沟通。
network: n.   网络
By using computers linked to telephone networks, nor could he have forcing how we could use
通过使用链接到电话网络的计算机，他也无法强迫我们如何使用
the internet to obtain information on every known. Subject, so we can read it on a screen in our
互联网获取有关每个已知的信息。主题，因此我们可以在我们的屏幕上阅读
homes and even print it as well if we want to. Computers have become smaller and smaller,
如果我们愿意，房屋也可以打印。计算机变得越来越小，
more and more powerful and cheaper and cheaper. This is what makes Leon Bagrid's predictions
越来越强大，更便宜，更便宜。这就是使莱昂·巴格里德（Leon Bagrid）预测的原因
particularly remarkable. If he or someone like him were alive today, he might be able to tell us
特别出色。如果他或像他这样的人今天还活着，他也许可以告诉我们
what to expect in the next 50 years.
未来50年的期望。